mmm-hmm I am excited today you know why
because we're gonna use so many
technologies we're gonna learn about
Mongo Express nodejs
to put together a full-on REST API I
don't worry if you don't know anything
about these we're gonna learn how to
connect to database we're gonna learn
how to make route and make API calls and
all the good stuff oh and since to you
guys like the last magic trick hey that
hold up hold up I got you so since we're
learning with tree technologies today
once we learn them we're gonna become
kings hello it's me Maria anyway okay
let's get going here
let's create a REST API so the first
thing I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go to
terminal here and I'm just gonna npm in
it which is gonna generate us that
package JSON file which does actually
not too much but it just holds us the
dependency so Hiram's is gonna hit enter
10,000 times until we have this package
JSON okay so this holds again all the
packages packages that we're gonna get
from the internet and the first package
I'm gonna install is something called
Express so let's do NPM install Express
like so I kinda it kind of reminds me of
Polar Express let me know if you've seen
that in the comments okay so Express and
the other one is node Mon and hit enter
so we can install multiple multiple
packages here just by adding a space and
then the other packages name you can
also add that node Mon into your dev
dependencies if that's something you
wish but for now this is gonna be super
simple and it's gonna be fine so after
everything is installed we can close up
this terminal a bit and we can go to
package dot JSON here and as you can see
it holds our packages Wow amazing good
job packages and you're doing your job
okay the first thing we're gonna do is
I'm gonna remove this script here and
I'm gonna add a start okay and here make
sure to add double quotes here here and
here as well because it's not gonna work
if you're not gonna do that
don't blame me for it I'm not the reason
why doesn't work and here we can just
add node Mon fjs which we are going to
create now so this is a script that's
going to
helped us execute and run our server
okay that's all it does close that up
we're gonna create a new file called fjs
now if you remember again we did it like
so if you added the HTTP we require the
HTTP and then we created the server and
Jesus Christ okay nobody wants to do
that so now look at Express it's gonna
be very awesome so the first thing we're
gonna do is we're gonna import Express
by saying cost Express equals to require
Express that just gets us the package
into this file the second thing we are
going to do is we are going to execute
this Express so the way you're gonna see
online and everywhere is people are
gonna create this app variable and
they're gonna just execute Express on
top of it and now you have the ability
to create routes in a very very simple
way so I'm just gonna add a comment here
with routes okay if if you're blind like
me I'm gonna zoom in a bit there we go
hopefully this is a bit more visible now
and let's create a route but before we
create a route how do we start listening
listening to the server like how do we
boot up the server well look at this
it's super simple
all you have to do say app dot listen
and you give a deed name that the port
name that you want to listen to so for
example three thousand and done that's
it now we can create a route and I'm
gonna explain what's happening here in
just a bit for now let's just create
that we can do app get and you can pass
a route add a comma here and then you
have your request and response like we
did in node and now I can just send a
message if I want with response so res
dots and I'll just say we are on home
okay the home home slash home URL okay
and that's it we can reopen up the
terminal or up here if you want and we
can just do NPM start so we are running
that script from package thought Jason
perfect let's take a look in here
as you can see if I hit enter we have
the message we are on home so everything
works wow that's that's that's pretty
cool it's like three lines of code so
what's happening here well we import the
package we execute it and with that we
can create routes so we can use this app
to create routes now yet all it means is
that it shoots us back a message if we
want to send a message so like
submitting a form like a login form then
we would use something like post okay
that gives it we can also delete
something so you can imagine we have a
post list then I want to remove a
certain post I can use delete and in
here you would add a logic to remove
that post and we have delete and we also
have something called patch which
updates for example a post okay so you
would use patch for updating the lead
for deleting gets to get the information
post to give the information yeah and in
here the first parameter we have is the
route that we want to go to
so this executes when we go to slash so
just localhost
so nothing here if I want maybe this to
go to slash posts like this slash post I
would create another route to do that so
I can copy this and paste it down here
and I can add posts like so and now I
can change this we are on home - we are
on posts and go back here and now if I
go to posts and hit enter we are on
posts so as you can see it's super super
easy to create these routes with Express
and as you can see here here all we do
is just respond to the user by sending a
message here which is a string Wow super
cool okay there's another concept that
we need to talk about before we can
create this this REST API is something
called middlewares in an express and
although middleware is you can imagine
it as just being a function that
executes when a specific
when routes are being hit and let's say
when we are hitting this slash here we
can run a function that's always gonna
execute when we hit this route so let's
take a look on how we can do that and we
can kind of restrict it so for example
for it to only hit when we are on posts
so let's take a look let's do it with
the posts so the way you can create a
middleware is you just say add dot use
and here you specify the route that you
want it to execute we can do posts and
then here we can just create a function
and let's say whenever we hit this post
I can always run this function and I'm
just gonna say hello this is a
middleware running all right so we can
add some logic here to run every time we
hit this post so hit save and let's take
a look here when we are on home and hit
enter let's take a look what we have in
our console and we don't have anything
so that's good but when we go to posts
slash posts hit enter look at that now
we have this is a middleware running so
we can execute these small functions and
you're gonna see that we're gonna use
some packages to add as middlewares
even like authentification you can
imagine that we can use like some
identification and here aught so every
time we hit a route then this is always
gonna check if the user is authenticated
you know so every time we go to a
specific route this is gonna run okay so
that's kind of the point of middlewares
alright let's remove this because we
don't need that to console.log it's
pointless
and the first thing we are gonna do is
we are gonna let's let's connect to a
database so to connect to a database
we're gonna use MongoDB and Mongoose
which is a package that's gonna help us
make everything way way easier and
MongoDB is actually a document type
which doesn't really have relations so
you can imagine it as being it just a
one huge object that's pouring a lot of
information so you don't have like
relations and pay
and things of that sort of you know SQL
Mongoose kind of gives you that ability
and it makes connecting to a database
and everything very easy so we're gonna
use that for now just because of its
simplicity so I'm gonna close up the
server by doing ctrl C and we're gonna
install NPM install Mongoose here it's M
o n G o OS e there we go hit enter and
let that sucker install and now what
we're gonna do is we are gonna go to
something called M lab so let's go to M
lab dot-com and here we can use a free
database it gives us like half a
gigabyte which is very nice just to kind
of experiment and prototype with it okay
so we're now gonna download it and
because it can get kind of complicated
there to make it make it work so
depending if you're on Windows or Mac OS
so let's let's keep it simple for now
let's just go on M lab you can create an
account and once you're on your account
then you can go up here to manage and we
can create a new server a database so we
can go here to create new we're gonna
hit that and now we can go to sandbox
here which is free we can head down here
continue and we can choose a server I'm
gonna use Europe hit next we can give it
a name I'm gonna give it a rest
that's gonna be the name and hit submit
and there we go that's gonna give us the
database let's wait a bit there we go
and it's in progress which is fine until
that happens but it should happen quite
quickly actually there we go
okay gave you a refresh I'm gonna hit
click on it and the way we can connect
to it is with this link up here it says
to connect use driver blah blah blah
blah here okay so this is what we need
here but as you can see it's gonna ask
us for a DB user and a password so this
is something that we need to create now
how can you create that all you have to
do is go here to the users so click on
this one and you can add a database user
so this is
just so you can access this that
database you can have multiple people
here that can access your database for
now let's just do test boy and I'm gonna
do 1 2 3 4 5 6 and password must contain
at least one alphabetic character I'm
gonna do Rhino 94 Rhino 94 that's fine
create ok perfect we have that now the
problem is that we cannot store this URL
with the password and the DB user and
here when we connect because well people
when we push up this code people can see
the user name and the password so that's
not good so the way we can hide that is
by installing a package we can do NPM
install dot and E and V so dot M okay
hit install there we go we're gonna wait
for it for a bit and let's try to
connect to our database so let's go down
here and for now we're gonna hard code
it and I'm gonna just add connect to DB
here like so and the way we can do that
is we can import this mongoose package
so Mongoose equals to require Mongoose
perfect and down here what we can do is
just say Mongoose dot connect and then
we can pass and that URL so let's go
back here and let's copy this and we're
gonna change this later a bit so don't
worry I'm not gonna hard code this in
here but what you do is you just change
this dbusername'
all you do is add your username and
password that you added on em lab so in
here I added Rhino 94 and what you can
also be here after this string you can
pass an arrow function and just
console.log I just console.log connected
to dB okay just a quick message to let
us know that everything works here okay
that's that's it let's open up our
console here in the same and
p.m. start and let's see if we get that
message so there we go connected to DB
and we're getting this deprecation
warning here and we can fix that by they
just say that you need to pass this new
URL parser so we're just gonna copy this
from here and I'm just gonna pass it
next to here okay and then I'm gonna add
a comma right after right before this
arrow function so let me go back here so
I just add the comma actually let me hit
save okay so we just pass the string we
add this object here with new our URL
parser and then we have our function
here to just say hey we connected and as
you can see now we don't have that
deprecation warning any more perfect now
again we don't want a hard code this so
we installed that that dot E and V
package story we can hide this is we can
create a dot e MV file and here I can
add a a kind of special message here or
a key or a code or anything that I don't
want anybody to see and and the way we
can do that is I can just give it a name
so for example this is DB connection
connection okay and I can set this equal
to this text in here so I'm gonna copy
this and paste it in here okay so this
is how it looks and we can hit save and
now to use this again remember we are
not gonna push this code up to github or
anything that's not EMV so because
people are gonna see our password and
everything so we can just get rid of
this and the way we can use it is by
going up here and requiring that dot EMV
package like so and we're gonna add a
slash convict okay here you don't need
to create a variable name before it it's
just gonna work and once you require
this package we have access to this dot
E and V this DB connection here by right
process dot e MV dot DB connection okay
that's it
hit save let's take a look are we still
connecting Hey there we go were
connected to our database so that's
super perfect okay now this file can get
quite crazy as you can see it gets kind
of crazy so what we can do is we can
actually remove these routes from here
and add them into their own kind of file
and we can import them in here and use
them so let's take a look on how we can
do that we can create a folder here
called route and maybe this is just
handling posts so we can create a new
file that's called posts like that dot J
s okay and what we can do here is we can
import that express again require
Express and what we can also do is call
const router set this equal to Express
router and call this as a function and
now what we can do is we can kind of
create our own routes in separate files
and just import it into this app dot J s
and it's all gonna make sense in a bit
so now we can use this router rather
than the app to create our routes so we
can do rather than get and we can do
slash posts and we can just say request
and response and we can actually just
copy everything from here and paste it
in here and change this to router and
now we can just module dot exports set
this equal to that router so we're
exporting this router so you can kind of
configure this so you can have a post
router you can maybe have a user's
router and things like that okay so you
can you can make everything more clean
and your folder structure and everything
okay so we have this one hope you're
still with me because I'm lost already
I'm tired again ok so we have this now
the cool thing is that maybe I don't
want to keep
of having like slash posts and things of
that sort so we can use a middleware we
can bring this posts from here to a BAS
so import route
I can just say Const posts routes route
posts route is equal to require and I'll
just go to that folder so posts there we
go and now rather than the way we can do
that do it is we can go here and we can
just do AB dot use so we can create the
middleware and now I'm gonna say every
time you go to that posts make sure to
use this post route ok and now here the
cool thing is I don't have to add this
posts anymore here because every time
we're gonna go to posts these post
routes are gonna run so let's take a
look let's go back here to our localhost
and hit enter and we should still see
that we are on posts now the cool thing
here is that if I want to add more I can
just go here and just add maybe a
specific post so maybe post dot specific
and hit enter and this is gonna be a
specific post hit save and now if we go
back to the browser
I can just go slash specific and that's
not correct because I might misspell
this let's go back again to the browser
and there we go hit enter and as you can
see we are on specific post so the
reason we're doing this with the
middleware here is you can have multiple
middleware so you can use AB dot use
maybe have a user slash user and you
have a user route ok you can create a
new file for that as well now I don't
have to worry about adding here posts
and everything slash whatever whatever I
always know that in here and my post
route this is always gonna bring me to
that post so whatever you have in that
fjs and if you want to attach more
things to it and then you can do it here
like we did here with the specific so
this may be a bit weird but it's it's
very effective and all you have to do
again is just create a route export that
router here and then just bring it into
the app is and use it as a middleware
and that's it that's all you have to do
so we have AB dot use posts here which
is great and now we can only work here
ok that's perfect and let's see what we
are gonna need so here I'm gonna leave
this we are on home that's completely
fine and now what we're gonna need to do
is we are going to need to create some
data so we can store it in our database
because we have nothing now and the way
we do that is with Mongoose is we create
these models so let me just show you
because it's gonna make a lot of sense
once I show you so we're gonna create a
new folder called model here our models
hit enter and then you just create a
post model so I'm gonna uppercase this
spacing post dot J s hit enter ok and
here I'm gonna import that Mongoose
package require Mongoose Thanks so
perfect and we are gonna create a schema
now now what the schema means it just
represents how that post looks so maybe
it has a a title and that's a string
maybe it has some description so you
kind of describe the way your data looks
that's that that's it that's what a
schema is so let's create it we can be
const post schema and we can set this
equal to Mongoose dot schema okay we're
getting that functionality from Mongoose
and here we just create an object like
so and now we can just describe the
properties that we want to use so maybe
my post has a title okay and that's a
string that's it that's all you have to
do maybe I have a description I can add
a description and that's gonna be a
string and maybe I have a price I don't
know why you would have a price
so I just get rid of this and we can
also do date if we want okay maybe these
are the only three properties we want
and we can just do date thought now okay
now what if I want to add validation to
this or maybe I need this to be required
okay this cannot be left empty that way
we can do this we can remove this string
and we can just add an object here and
now we can describe multiple things so I
can add a type of string so the way we
did it but maybe I want this to be
required so I can add required true and
I can actually copy and paste this to
the next one
so in here because this is gonna be the
same and for the date I can also add a
type date there we go and we can also
add a default if we want we can save a
thought now and hit save so there we go
again this just kind of describes the
way our data is gonna look our post data
you can imagine that we have a user
schema that's all it's gonna be is like
Mongoose dot schema and then you can
define the user schema maybe you have a
user name that's gonna be a type string
a password and a string okay and you can
have date or maybe user info so it just
kind of describes the way your data
looks that's all it is and at the end
once we have the schema all we do is we
module that exports we export this and
we set this equal to Mangusta model and
now we give it a name so I'm gonna give
it post and this model is the thing
that's gonna show up in our EM lab so
you're gonna see posts show up okay so
we give this the name and the schema
that it should use so we're gonna say
post kheema and that's it I promise
that's it there we go so we create that
model we give it a name and we give a
disk image to use and that's it that's
all we need to do we can close out of
this and we can just straight up work
and this posts
so let's let's try the get back let's
try to add a post okay let's try to
create one so the first thing you would
do is you would import you would go up
here and you would import then model
that you want to post to so we're gonna
say Const post equals require then we
can go back to the model we need to add
double dots here dot dot slash we need
to go to models slash post there we go
it's safe so we go back this post and
now what we can do is let's go down here
there we go and we can just say router
dot post because we want to post
something to it and the route is gonna
be slash and then we can add a comma
then we're gonna have request and
response thanks umm perfect here we go
we're gonna open this up and the way we
can create a new post is by saying cons
post okay I'm just going to create an
object here and what we need to do is we
are gonna have to access the information
so the thing that we're posting to our
API from the body so request dot body
and we can actually console.log that out
to see what we get back so console.log
request dot body and I'm just no I'm
just gonna leave it at this for now
because we are gonna need another
package to make this work so how can we
test this out so how can we post things
delete things without actually creating
a react app or without using the browser
so it very cool thing that we have is
something called postman so you can
search up postman and this is the first
one right here and you can download it
it's super simple and this is again just
gonna help us test out our API in very
simple ways so let me open this up here
let me close this we're gonna say
postman come on my friend this laptop is
killing me alright there we go so we're
opening a postman here
and it's taking too much it's too long
there we go I'm I need to reinstall mine
because it's giving me an s nasty error
but anyway we can close this up even
this one we can close this up and as you
can see here now we can make a get
request if we want so let's try to make
a get request to this post all I have to
do is copy this and paste it in here and
I want to do get requests and when I hit
Send as you can see I get back that
message we are on posts perfect now how
can I submit one we can just go to post
here
and now I want to make sure I go to body
here let me delete this and you can
choose if you have it on form data you
can choose raw and you can go to JSON
application JavaScript here not
application JSON application JSON here
and now you can submit data you can
imagine that your kind of doing this
with on a react okay front-end but we
can just do it here so the way we can
submit to it is we can create an object
here like so let me can zoom in here so
you can see there we go actually more
and now we can just define the things
that we defined and our model so how is
our post model looking like well let's
take a look so let me open up the code
here and it takes a title a description
we don't need to provide the date
because it's gonna jump to this default
now so all we need to do is just add a
title and description so let's try it so
we can do a title and I'm just gonna say
make sure to add double quotes here
title and we're gonna say my first post
and then we can also add a description
again make sure you add those double
quotes and a comma at the end here this
is my description of my love life why
would you do that I'm not sure but hey
Yolo okay so we have this going here I'm
gonna fullscreen this
and now when we click send as you can
see this is loading nothing really
happens here which is fine but if we go
back to our our app here we're gonna see
that we get undefined down here hmm why
is that happening well the problem is
that we cannot process that that request
that's coming in in our body we're gonna
need a special package that's going to
convert this to JSON for us okay so this
is not gonna work by default so the way
we can do that is there's a package
called body parser which is gonna do
exactly that it's gonna parse our our
request and it's gonna give us back the
correct way to handle that data so we
can just npm install body parser like so
okay hits enter it's about waiting again
so there's a lot of waiting with
installing these packages so all you
have to do is up here let's go back to
our App KS and we just add that package
so we say Const body parser is equal to
require body parts are like so and now
we just create one of those middlewares
we can say have got use and every time
we hit any request we're gonna make sure
that this body parser runs okay so we're
gonna say body parser dot JSON like so
and that's it that's all we have to do
is one line of code
literally so npm start and let's take a
look again if that works so we're gonna
start up the server let's go back to
postman and hit send again on the posts
and let's take a look what we get now
look at that we are getting back the
title and description down there so
again it parses it and then make sure
the response comes back and we can work
with it that's all body parts or does so
now that we have this information we can
kind of work with it and post it to our
database so that's very cool so let's
take a look here
let's go back to our posts we can close
this up our Apogee yes we're not gonna
work in aperture does yes anymore let's
minimize that as well and in here in our
posts what we can do is delete this we
don't need this so just so you know we
have our information that we're sending
on this request dot body okay let's get
rid of this and we can create a new post
I'm just gonna say Const
equals to new post now what is this new
post well it's from here we are gonna
create a new post with this model that
we have up here and all we have to do is
call this function and pass in an object
in here okay and here we have a title
and where is that title coming from from
request body title we also have a
description that's coming again from
request body description okay hope
that's super clear okay so we have this
post now and we can save this to our
database by just saying post dot save
like so perfect and this actually
returns a promise and actually we need
to add something called exact which
makes it to return a promise and then
all we have to do is say then okay so
we're just doing a promise here we can
get back the data like so and then all
we have to do is say restaurant JSON
data so if I want to see it on the
screen this is all gonna do after we
posted data I'm just gonna put it out on
the screen there so I'm just gonna
respond with a JSON and the data that
we're saving to our database and here we
can also catch if we have an error so
make sure to add dot catch here error
and here we can just run an arrow
function again and you can also respond
with a status code so here this would be
a 200 so you could do res dot status
like 200 but I
want to overcomplicate with you you can
take a look at the status codes if you
want to know more you're proud you
probably know 404 which means that it's
not found so that's kind of when you
will see what you would use these
statuses for so we for this one we can
just say rest JSON and we can just send
back that error message we can even do
one if we want we can create a object
here with a message of error hit save
and yeah let's take a look if this works
let's go here and now we add this and we
hit send and we get an error is gonna
say post out saved is not a function so
let's take a look why this is happening
and I apologize I don't think we
actually need need this exec anymore
we can just hit save here let's take a
look now and hit send again and there we
go look we have that object created and
we can even take a look in our database
so let's go back to M lab in here there
we go let's hit refresh and we have our
rest yes there we go and we have posts
and there we go that's our model our
post model and we have two posts
actually I think I submitted this twice
so my first post and my first post so
let's get rid of one we can also get rid
of one by clicking on delete and as you
can see it also gives us an ID so this
is something automatically generated by
by Mongo and we have title description
and our date right down here so that's
super super cool and we can also
reformat this and async await if you
want and the way you can do that is all
you have to do is just add async up here
so before this request and response this
stays the same and here we just create a
cost and let's say saved post and we can
set this equal to a weight post dot save
and that's it and we can kind of
simplify this
get rid of this and then we have we can
just rest dot JSON these saved post so
this is a bit more cleaner now we can
wrap this in a try-catch like so so we
can try this and then we can catch an
error just in case
so catch and here we have access to an
error like so and we can just rest are
JSON a message with the error hit save
and let's see if that works the same way
we can go back to postman and here let's
say this is my second post and here we
can just change the description to my
love life this is kind of not great okay
and hit save here and we can send this
again and as you can see it works the
same way and we should have that data
available for us now let's actually
change up this router get here so we get
back all the posts because right now we
are not getting back all the posts and I
don't want this message we are on posts
who cares we won't back the data so the
way we can get that is again we can just
add that async if we want and we can do
a try-catch here like so catch we can
catch the error and here I can just
press that JSON the message of error
perfect and in our try what we can do is
we can just say cost posts so this is
all the posts that we're getting back
and we can await the response so we can
call post so again this is the model and
the way we can get back is by adding
find okay this is a method on Mongoose
and here again if you leave it empty
like this this is just gonna return all
the posts for you there's a lot of
things you can do look if you want you
can have a limit so you can return only
five posts if you want that is what you
wish for so you have a lot of options
options here but for now we're just
gonna return everything and that's gonna
be fine we can say rest out JSON and we
can send back that response so
and that's it let's take a look we are
on post we can go to get and when we hit
Send look we are getting back the whole
lists of all of our posts let's do
another post request here and on the
posts we can go back to the body let's
and eat another one just so we have tree
this is my final post my final YouTube
video parenthesis emotional okay
click baiting perfect and the
description is gonna be buy my merch
alright and hit Send and we should get
another one so we can go back again to
the get its sent and now we have pre
posts here so that's very very cool okay
what else do we need to do well let's
try to get a specific post so this one
gets back all the posts this one submits
a post and down here we can let's get
back a son which I will let's get back a
specific post specific post okay the way
we can do that is we can do browser yet
again
okay get because we want to get back one
specific post and rather than adding
only slash we can do slash and we can do
call on here and we can give it a name
so like post ID or something post ID and
here we have our request and response
and let me cancel log out this post I be
so you know what it is I can just say
console.log request dot params got post
IB so this is where we have it we have
access to it okay
let's save and basically this is kind of
like a dynamic parameter so anything you
add after posts so let's take a look
here anything you add after here the
is gonna be that post ID and we can
access it with request params post ID so
let me just show you the example because
we are council logging it here and this
route so if we go back here what we can
do is just say this is the per am and
when we hit send all right this is gonna
block but that's fine because we're just
console logging but as you can see here
on our console well this is our per am
so okay that's cool but what can we do
with this well we can find a specific
post by the URL so what we can do we can
delete this and we can say post okay be
model again so whenever you want to do
anything to to submit data or get data
we can use them model that we created in
here and what we can do is say post and
again you have a ton of methods here
that you can have fun with one of them
is called find buy ID which we're going
to use here and we are gonna find that
ID by this parameter here request params
da post ID okay that's it and then you
can do something with the response so
again we can use that async here and
just store this into a single post said
this equals that and make sure you add a
weight because this might take some time
because it's coming from a database and
then what we can do is we can just say
res dot send or JSON and we can send
that post perfect again we can wrap it
in a try-catch just to be safe here like
so and we can catch just make sure if we
have an error then we are gonna read
that JSON that message with the error
it's safe and let's take a look so when
we are getting all the posts now if I
had sent here we're getting back an
error because there's no such thing with
this ID as this is the per am but look
at this if we go to posts and hit send
while we are getting back all the
information and let's let me just copy
one of these IDs here
oh my let's do this one the last one
this this is my final YouTube video
emotional and if I copied the ID from
here and I paste it at the end of this
URL and hit Send as you can see now it
just returns that specific URL on that
specific post just because just because
of this of this post ID and we can pass
it down and here to search for a
specific post and this way you can
delete a post or update the post using
this pram so let's take a look on how we
can delete one it's gonna be very simple
we're gonna go down here we're gonna say
delete a specific post down here all we
have to do is a router dot delete so
this is gonna be a delete method here we
can do the same thing we can add post ID
we can do request and response might
wrote is super dry but that's fine
and here now what we can do is again we
can use that model to do something with
our data so I'm gonna call post and we
have a method here called remove and
that's exactly what it's gonna do it's
gonna remove a specific post so this
takes an object here and we can remove
something with a specific ID so I'm
adding underscore here if you cannot see
that let me zoom in that's too much
ahead what are you doing I'm adding this
underscore here because as you can see
that's the thing that Mongo generates
for us automatically so I'm searching
basically by that criteria zoom out a
bit n that's fine okay so here what I do
is just say this IB needs to match that
thing that's coming from my request
params post ID okay so this one perfect
let's hit save and again this is gonna
come back with a promise so let's say he
sync and I'm gonna store this construe
moved post or something and said this
equals that make sure we await this
and we are they try catch again you can
kind of actually copy/paste this and
just modify that if this is taking too
long we get back the error here and I
can just copy-paste this from up here
it's safe so once we have that removed
post I can just send back let's just do
a rest JSON with the removed post okay
it's safe now the cool thing is all I
have to do is once I am on this post so
maybe I want to delete this and I want
to keep continuing to make awesome
videos on YouTube and we can just go to
delete and now since I have the same ID
here I can just hit Send and look at
that we're getting back this weird
message it's gonna say here delete count
let's let's make sure that we deleted
this post so we can go back to the get
request here and we can just delete this
IP and just call it this posts so we can
get back all the posts and look at that
we deleted the last one so that's good
now the final thing I want to show you
is how we can update one so let's go
back here and the way we can update one
is by using something called patch so
update a post and let's say I want to
update a title of a specific post so all
we have to do is call router dot patch
that's gonna update it I can do the same
thing so everything kind of repeats
itself here and we can call a method
called on the post again update one and
I can pass that thing and that we did
here so the criteria that we are
searching from like we did here and you
remove so I can just copy this and paste
it in here like that so again we're
searching by this we can use async again
here and let me just what are we copying
let's just copy the catch here then I'll
wrap it in a try-catch alright let's get
rid of this
so try and then we catch perfect so we
get this let's store it somewhere Const
updated post equal to you a wait post
updated one so this is the one that we
are gonna wait for now this takes
another property here so we have this
object that is the search criteria and
the next one is gonna be another object
that you wanna change a specific
information so here what I wanted to is
actually add something called dollar
sign set okay and here you add a colon
and another pair of objects here so this
is this takes another object in here
here what you would do is you just say
maybe I want to change the title so I
can see title and that's coming from
request body title okay let's save so
this is how it kinda looks we have
updated one we have this and then we set
the new value in here okay and finally
what we do is in here we just say cost
let's just output this actually I just
say res dot JSON and then we post that
updated post okay hit save and now we
can go back here and I want let's say I
want to change the title of the second
post so I'm gonna copy this ID paste it
in here I'm gonna switch to patch and
now in my body I can just delete this
and just update the title if I want so
for the title I'm gonna just change this
to you we are learning about backend
stuff and hit Send let's take a look and
as you can see we get back a response
with it says and modified here and some
other fun stuff that to be honest I
truly I don't understand everything in
here but hey it is what it is but at the
end of the day if we go to get now and
go to post and hit
then we should get look we are learning
about back-end stuff so that specific
part of the code of the information
updated and our description is still my
love life is kind of not rain
it's okay alright so there we go we did
we wrote we got information we posted
information we delete deleted
information and everything all right so
let's see how this can work and how we
can use it actually in the browser so
I'm gonna do this very quickly we're not
gonna implement it in a react project if
you want to see like how you can work
with API is and stuff like that check
out my react for beginners you should
have that up there and I think we work
with like two or three api's but for now
let me just kind of give you an example
what problem you might run into you once
you have this server running so maybe
here you would do something like let me
zoom in here a bit so maybe I want to
fetch that I want to fetch all the posts
so the way we're doing here right I'm
just gonna copy that I'm gonna say fetch
so the posts in here and then you would
get back the result and let's just call
so log the result okay let's let's hit
tab why you do this to me close up hit
tab and we should this should not work
okay it's gonna say access to fetch
local those three thousand posts from
origin code pan has been blocked by
course policy No
okay you're gonna have this problem a
lot of times you're gonna have this
error and you're gonna say why is this
happening to my life and the reason why
this is happening is because look if we
are on localhost 3000 we are only able
to make requests on localhost 3000 you
can imagine this as I have my own API on
dev ed calm and you have your own
website on Julia Roberts calm okay Julia
Roberts cannot make requests to my API
on my domain because by default they
have this access control origin blockage
thing okay so this only works if again
it you can
imagine is I have my website that's
David calm and I have my note server
running there if I have my client code
so my client react project on are still
on David calm that everything is going
to work fine but if I have my API on
David calm and I have my react project
on Judah is why am I saying Judah just
another domain it's not gonna work okay
you cannot do that cross domain fetching
but we can fix that we can go back here
to our our project and we can actually
allow it to use across all the domains
so we can install a package from this we
can close up this with ctrl C Y and we
can NPM install cores hit enter we're
gonna wait a bit
did 32 term all right once its installed
all we have to do is that is just to add
that middleware so let's go back to fjs
here and we can do it let's do above
here because we have our middlewares
here middlewares
and we're using the body parser and we
can also use that course and all you
have to do is just say AB dot use and
you just say course and you invoke that
function and that's it simple as that we
can run the function and we can start up
the server again npm start and let's
let's take a look let's pray for the
gods
oh no course is not define okay we need
to import it and what are you doing
Const course equals require course yay
hit save do you still hate me no okay he
doesn't hate me
let's go back to code pen and try this
again hit refresh come on data come back
to us why there we go we have the
response
Hey look at that we have the response
everything works fine now
so we can extract that by saying now if
I just convert it to JSON here so I'm
gonna return this resolved Jason and
just console.log deep data we should
have this let's take a look look at that
we have the array with both of our
objects and now we can work with this
and use it in our HTML and there we go
look we got the data from an external
API that we created there we go we put
together all three technologies to
create a simple REST API let me know if
you want to see user identification and
things like that how we can hash
passwords and if you want to see that I
am here for you okay I'm here I'm I'm
bored and I have nothing to do all right
and let me know if you want to see other
magic tricks because I have some more
right there in the background that you
cannot see it the first sure a lot of
the magic tricks behind me happening so
okay all right I'll see you next time
have a great day